<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abouts on Vincent Lecrubier</title>
    <link>https://crubier.github.io/about/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abouts on Vincent Lecrubier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2017 Vincent Lecrubier</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://crubier.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://crubier.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crubier.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;French &lt;strong&gt;Computer science PhD, entrepreneur, aerospace engineer, Olympic kayaker&lt;/strong&gt;. A massive geek in everything related to Aerospace, Computer Science and new technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://crubier.github.io/img/Identity.png&#34; alt=&#34;This is me&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;professional-experience&#34;&gt;Professional experience&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016-Present&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Vice-president&lt;/strong&gt; of the French Canoe Federation (FFCK), an Olympic sport federation totaling 45,000 Members and a 6M€ budget. In charge of digital development, relationship with private companies, and high level sport.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015-Present&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;CTO, co-founder of Sterblue&lt;/strong&gt;. Sterblue develops drone-based industrial inspection solutions. Managing more than 20 individuals developing embedded software, cloud and web-based software, and machine learning applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011-2016&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Computer scientist, PhD candidate at the French aerospace lab&lt;/strong&gt; (ONERA) in Toulouse, France. Developed a formal language for safety-critical user interface specification. Presented this work in international conferences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010-2012&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Representative for the French Ministry of Defense&lt;/strong&gt;, during a two-year sponsorship program for high level sportsmen and sportswomen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010-2011&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;One-year Intern at Airbus&lt;/strong&gt; (EYMM Department). Improving processes, methods and tools for embedded user interface specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2003-2016&lt;/strong&gt;: Member of the &lt;strong&gt;French kayak team for 4 Olympiads&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;education-and-awards&#34;&gt;Education and awards&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;ISAE-Supaero Special prize&lt;/strong&gt; First-ever recipient, recognizing my professional cursus and my involvement in social activities of the school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;PhD in Mathematics and Computer Sciences at ONERA&lt;/strong&gt;. Developing a formal language for safety-critical user interface specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;NATO&lt;/strong&gt; Dependable Software Systems Engineering Summer School in Marktoberdof, Germany, with professors who are ACM Turing Award winners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Supaéro engineer’s degree&lt;/strong&gt; at ISAE (the French Aerospace Engineering Institute), majoring in Computer Science, Aerodynamics and Embedded Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Business and Management Engineering diploma&lt;/strong&gt; (DESIA) at ISAE (the French Aerospace Engineering Institute)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Sportsman of the year&lt;/strong&gt; in Britanny, France.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Ranked 49th nationaly&lt;/strong&gt; at “X - ENS Cachan” competitive entrance exam to French “Grandes écoles”, admitted to ENS, integrated in Supaéro/ISAE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Scientific Baccalaureate&lt;/strong&gt; (Mathematics and Engineering) with Honors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;high-level-sport-flat-water-sprint-kayaking&#34;&gt;High-level sport, Flat water sprint kayaking&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2000-Present&lt;/strong&gt;: Totaling more than &lt;strong&gt;30 French champion titles&lt;/strong&gt;, and more than &lt;strong&gt;10 world cup medals&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;: First substitute for the &lt;strong&gt;London Olympic games&lt;/strong&gt;, 7th place at the European Championships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Vice World Champion&lt;/strong&gt; in K4-1000m&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Beijing Olympic games&lt;/strong&gt;, 7th place in K2-500m, Delegate of French team athletes with the French Kayak Federation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2003-2004&lt;/strong&gt;: Four World silver medals in K1-1000m, K2-500m, K1, K2 marathon Junior, 3rd in K2-1000m&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;skills&#34;&gt;Skills&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;languages&#34;&gt;Languages&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;French&lt;/strong&gt;: Native&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;: Full professional proficiency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spanish&lt;/strong&gt;: Good working knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portuguese&lt;/strong&gt;: Beginner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;software-development&#34;&gt;Software development&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embedded Software&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;C, C++&lt;/strong&gt;, Objective-C, ADA, real time systems, Scade, Lustre, Xenomai, Linux RT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientific Software&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Python, Numpy, TensorFlow, Mathematica&lt;/strong&gt;, Matlab, Simulink, CATIA, Solid Works, Open Frameworks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;SQL&lt;/strong&gt; (PostgreSQL, MariaDB&amp;hellip;) and &lt;strong&gt;NoSQL&lt;/strong&gt; Databases (MongoDB, Redis, Neo4J, Arangodb&amp;hellip;), &lt;strong&gt;GraphQL&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Node JS, React JS, Docker&lt;/strong&gt;, Angular JS, Java, Javascript, RDF, XML/XSLT&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User interfaces&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Web Apps, Qt, iOS, ARINC 661&lt;/strong&gt;, Swift, Java Swing, SWT, Max/MSP, OpenGL&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;licenses&#34;&gt;Licenses&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private pilot license&lt;/strong&gt; (PPL-A) ongoing (35 flight hours)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yachtmaster Coastal Certificate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Driving license&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;interests-and-projects&#34;&gt;Interests and Projects&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drones&lt;/strong&gt;: Design and operation of micro aerial vehicles, OpenPilot project member, project leader at Supaero Micro Air Vehicle club, created a unique 6-DOF Tilt-Quadcopter design, patented another UAV configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data science&lt;/strong&gt;: Developed an &lt;strong&gt;Inertial data processing framework&lt;/strong&gt; for the French Kayak Team to study the dynamics of kayaking using big data techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sports&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Outdoor sports enthusiast&lt;/strong&gt; with 15h per week running, swimming, mountain biking, skiing, sailing, wakeboarding, hiking&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arts&lt;/strong&gt;: Digital arts, algorithmic sound and video generation, sound synthesis, photography, video&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>